export const JambMaths = [
  {
    question: "Find r, if 6r78 = 5119",
    options: ["5", "2", "3", "6"],
    answer: "3",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A student measures a piece of rope and found that it was 1.26 m long. If the actual length of the rope was 1.25 m, what was the percentage error in the measurement?",
    options: ["0.40%", "0.01%", "0.25%", "0.80%"],
    answer: "0.80%",
  },
  {
    question:
      "At what rate will interest on ₦400 increase to ₦24 in 3 years reckoning in simple interest?",
    options: ["4%", "2%", "3%", "5%"],
    answer: "2%",
  },
  {
    question: "Express the product of 0.21 and 0.34 in standard form",
    options: ["7.14 x 10⁻³", "7.14 x 10⁻¹", "7.14 x 10⁻²", "7.14 x 10⁻⁴"],
    answer: "7.14 x 10⁻²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a survey of 50 newspaper readers, 40 read Champion and 30 read Guardian, how many read both papers?",
    options: ["15", "5", "10", "20"],
    answer: "20",
  },
  {
    question: "Make Q the subject of the formula if P(X + Q) + 1",
    options: ["Q = P - X", "Q = 1 - P", "Q = X + 1 - P", "Q = P(X + 1)"],
    answer: "Q = X + 1 - P",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If 9x² + 6xy + 4y² is a factor of 27x³ - 8y³, find the other factor.",
    options: ["3x - 2y", "2y - 3x", "2y + 3x", "3x + 2y"],
    answer: "3x - 2y",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve for x and y if x - y = 2 and x² - y² = 8",
    options: ["(1, 3)", "(3, 1)", "(-1, 3)", "(-3, 1)"],
    answer: "(3, 1)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If y varies directly as the square root of x and y = 3 when x = 16, calculate y when x = 64",
    options: ["5", "12", "6", "3"],
    answer: "6",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve the inequalities -6 ≤ 4 - 2x < 5 - x",
    options: ["-1 ≤ x < 6", "-1 < x ≤ 5", "-1 < x < 5", "-1 ≤ x ≤ 6"],
    answer: "-1 < x ≤ 5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the sum to infinity of the following series: 0.5 + 0.05 + 0.005 + 0.0005 + ....",
    options: ["0.5555", "0.5005", "0.555", "0.505"],
    answer: "0.5555",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The 3rd term of an arithmetic progression is -9 and the 7th term is -29. Find the 10th term of the progression",
    options: ["44", "-165", "-44", "55"],
    answer: "-44",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If p and q are two non-zero numbers and 18(p + q) = (18 + p)q, which of the following must be true?",
    options: ["q = 18", "p = 18", "p < 1", "q < 1"],
    answer: "q = 18",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the two smaller sides of a right-angled triangle are 4 cm and 5 cm, find its area.",
    options: ["10 cm²", "6 cm²", "8 cm²", "24 cm²"],
    answer: "10 cm²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An arc subtends an angle of 50° at the centre of a circle of radius 6cm. Calculate the area of the sector formed.",
    options: ["15.71 cm²", "31.42 cm²", "47.12 cm²", "62.83 cm²"],
    answer: "15.71 cm²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A cylindrical pipe 50cm long with radius 7m has one end open. What is the total surface area of the pipe?",
    options: ["700π m²", "98π m²", "350π m²", "749π m²"],
    answer: "749π m²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the locus of a point that is equidistant from points P(1, 3) and Q(3, 5)?",
    options: ["y = -x + 6", "y = x + 6", "y = -x - 6", "y = x - 6"],
    answer: "y = -x + 6",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the gradient of the line passing through the points P(1, 1) and Q(2, 5).",
    options: ["4", "2", "3", "5"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the equation of a line parallel to y = -4x + 2 passing through (2,3).",
    options: [
      "y - 4x + 11 = 0",
      "y - 4x - 11 = 0",
      "y + 4x + 11 = 0",
      "y + 4x - 11 = 0",
    ],
    answer: "y + 4x - 11 = 0",
  },
  {
    question: "If y = (2x + 1)³, find dy/dx.",
    options: ["3(2x+1)²", "3(2x + 1)", "6(2x + 1)", "6(2x+1)²"],
    answer: "6(2x+1)²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "At what value of X does the function f(x) = -3 - 2x + x² attain a minimum value?",
    options: ["1", "-4", "-1", "4"],
    answer: "-1",
  },
  {
    question: "Find ∫ (sin x + 2) dx.",
    options: [
      "cos x + x² + k",
      "cos x + 2x + k",
      "-cos x + 2x + k",
      "-cos x + x² + k",
    ],
    answer: "-cos x + 2x + k",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the standard deviation of 2, 3, 5, and 6.",
    options: ["1.58", "2.25", "3.14", "0.96"],
    answer: "1.58",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In how many ways can a committee of 2 women and 3 men be chosen from 6 men and 5 women?",
    options: ["50", "200", "100", "30"],
    answer: "200",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If three unbiased coins are tossed, find the probability that they are all heads.",
    options: ["1/8", "1/6", "1/4", "1/2"],
    answer: "1/8",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the numbers M, N, Q are in the ratio 5:4:3, find the value of",
    options: ["2", "3", "1", "4"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    question: "If log₃ 18 + log₃ 3 - log₃ x = 3, find x.",
    options: ["2", "9", "3", "6"],
    answer: "9",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Raial has 7 different posters to be hanged in her bedroom, living room and kitchen. Assuming she has plans to place at least a poster in each of the 3 rooms, how many choices does she have?",
    options: ["49", "170", "21", "210"],
    answer: "210",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the remainder when x³ - 2x² + 3x - 3 is divided by x² + 1.",
    options: ["2x - 1", "x + 3", "2x + 1", "x - 3"],
    answer: "2x - 1",
  },
  {
    question: "Factorize completely 9y² - 16x².",
    options: [
      "(3 - 2)(3 + 4)",
      "(3 + 4)(3 + 4)",
      "(3 + 2)(3 - 4)",
      "(3 - 4)(3 + 4)",
    ],
    answer: "(3 - 4)(3 + 4)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Solve for x and y respectively in the simultaneous equations -2x - 5y = 3, x + 3y = 0.",
    options: ["-3, -9", "9, -3", "-9, 3", "3, -9"],
    answer: "-9, 3",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If x varies directly as the square root of y and x = 81 when y = 9, find x when y = 1 7/9.",
    options: ["20", "27", "2", "36"],
    answer: "36",
  },
  {
    question:
      "T varies inversely as the cube of R. When R = 3, T = 2/81, find T when R = 2.",
    options: ["1/18", "1/12", "1/24", "1/6"],
    answer: "1/12",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve the inequality -6(x + 3) ≤ 4(x - 2).",
    options: ["x ≤ 2", "x ≥ -1", "x ≥ -2", "x ≤ -1"],
    answer: "x ≤ -1",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve the inequality 2 + 2 > 15.",
    options: [
      "x < -3 or x > 5",
      "-5 < x < 3",
      "x < 3 or x > 5",
      "x > 3 or x < -5",
    ],
    answer: "x < -3 or x > 5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the sum of the first 18 terms of the series 3, 6, 9..., 36.",
    options: ["505", "513", "433", "635"],
    answer: "513",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A binary operation ⊕ on real numbers is defined by x ⊕ y = xy + x + y for two real numbers x and y. Find the value of 3 ⊕ -2/3.",
    options: ["-1/2", "1/3", "-1", "2"],
    answer: "-1/2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the size of each interior angle of a 12-sided regular polygon?",
    options: ["120°", "150°", "30°", "180°"],
    answer: "150°",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A circle of perimeter 28 cm is opened to form a square. What is the maximum possible area of the square?",
    options: ["56 cm²", "49 cm²", "98 cm²", "28 cm²"],
    answer: "49 cm²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A chord of circle of radius 7 cm is 5 cm from the center of the circle. What is the length of the chord?",
    options: ["4√6 cm", "3√6 cm", "6√6 cm", "2√6 cm"],
    answer: "4√6 cm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A solid metal cube of side 3 cm is placed in a rectangular tank of dimensions 3, 4 and 5 cm. What volume of water can the tank now hold?",
    options: ["48 cm³", "33 cm³", "60 cm³", "27 cm³"],
    answer: "33 cm³",
  },
  {
    question: "The perpendicular bisector of a line XY is the locus of a point",
    options: [
      "whose distance from X is always twice its distance from Y",
      "whose distance from Y is always twice its distance from X",
      "which moves on the line XY",
      "which is equidistant from the points X and Y",
    ],
    answer: "which is equidistant from the points X and Y",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The midpoint of P(x, y) and Q(8, 6). Find x and y. Midpoint = (5, 8).",
    options: ["(2, 10)", "(2, 8)", "(2, 12)", "(2, 6)"],
    answer: "(2, 10)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the equation of a line perpendicular to line 2 = 5 + 4 which passes through (4, 2).",
    options: [
      "5 - 2 - 18 = 0",
      "5 + 2 - 18 = 0",
      "5 - 2 + 18 = 0",
      "5 + 2 - 2 = 0",
    ],
    answer: "5 + 2 - 18 = 0",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A man walks 100 m due West from a point X to Y, he then walks 100 m due North to a point Z. Find the bearing of X from Z.",
    options: ["195°", "135°", "225°", "045°"],
    answer: "225°",
  },
  {
    question: "The derivative of (2 + 1)(3 + 1) is",
    options: ["12x + 1", "6x + 5", "6x + 1", "12x + 5"],
    answer: "12x + 1",
  },
  {
    question: "Find ∫ cos 4 x dx.",
    options: [
      "¾ sin 4x + k",
      "-1/4 sin 4x + k",
      "-3/4 sin 4x + k",
      "1/4 sin 4x + k",
    ],
    answer: "-1/4 sin 4x + k",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In how many ways can the letters of the word ELATION be arranged?",
    options: ["6!", "7!", "5!", "8!"],
    answer: "7!",
  },
  {
    question: "In how many ways can five people sit round a circular table?",
    options: ["24", "60", "12", "120"],
    answer: "120",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the probability that a number picked at random from the set (43, 44, 45, ..., 60) is a prime number.",
    options: ["2/3", "1/3", "2/9", "7/9"],
    answer: "1/3",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a class of 60 students, 30 offer Physics and 40 offer Chemistry. If a student is picked at random from the class, what is the probability that the student offers both Physics and Chemistry?",
    options: ["1/3", "1/4", "1/2", "1/6"],
    answer: "1/3",
  },
  {
    question: "Convert 72 base 6 to a number in base 3",
    options: ["2211", "2121", "1212", "1122"],
    answer: "1122",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A man earns ₦3,500 per month out of which he spends 15% on his children's education. If he spends additional ₦1,950 on food, how much does he have left?",
    options: ["₦525", "₦1,025", "₦1,950", "₦2,975"],
    answer: "₦1,025",
  },
  {
    question: "If 27x + 2 ÷ 9x + 1 = 32x, find x",
    options: ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    question: "If log3(x²) = -8, what is x?",
    options: ["13", "19", "127", "181"],
    answer: "181",
  },
  {
    question: "Simplify (√6 + 2)² - (√6 + 2)²",
    options: ["2√6", "4√6", "8√6", "16√6"],
    answer: "8√6",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If P is a set of all prime factors of 30 and Q is a set of all factors of 18 less than 10, find P ∩ Q",
    options: ["{3}", "{2, 3}", "{2, 3, 5}", "{1, 2}"],
    answer: "{2, 3}",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a class of 46 students, 22 play football and 26 play volleyball. If 3 students play both games, how many play neither?",
    options: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    answer: "1",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the remainder when 2x³ - 11x² + 8x - 1 is divided by x + 3",
    options: ["-871", "-781", "-187", "-178"],
    answer: "-178",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve for x and y in the equations: x² - y² = 4, x + y = 2",
    options: ["x = 0, y = -2", "x = 0, y = 2", "x = 2, y = 0", "x = -2, y = 0"],
    answer: "x = 2, y = 0",
  },
  {
    question:
      "U is inversely proportional to the cube of V and U = 81 when V = 2. Find U when V = 3",
    options: ["24", "27", "32", "36"],
    answer: "24",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the range of values of m which satisfy (m - 3)(m - 4) < 0",
    options: ["2 < m < 5", "-3 < m < 4", "3 < m < 4", "-4 < m < 3"],
    answer: "3 < m < 4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The nth term of a sequence is n² - 6n - 4. Find the sum of the 3rd and 4th terms.",
    options: ["24", "23", "-24", "-25"],
    answer: "-25",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The binary operation * is defined on the set of integers such that p * q = pq + p - q. Find 2 * (3 * 4)",
    options: ["11", "13", "15", "22"],
    answer: "13",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The binary operation on the set of real numbers is defined by m * n = mn² for all m, n ∈ R. If the identity element is 2, find the inverse of -5",
    options: ["-45", "-25", "4", "5"],
    answer: "-25",
  },
  {
    question: "Given that I₃ is a unit matrix of order 3, find |I₃|",
    options: ["-1", "0", "1", "2"],
    answer: "1",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The angles of a polygon are given by x, 2x, 3x, 4x and 5x respectively. Find the value of x.",
    options: ["24°", "30°", "33°", "36°"],
    answer: "36°",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A circular arc subtends angle 150° at the center of a circle of radius 12 cm. Calculate the area of the sector of the arc.",
    options: ["30π cm²", "60π cm²", "120π cm²", "150π cm²"],
    answer: "60π cm²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Calculate the volume of a cuboid of length 0.76 cm, breadth 2.6 cm, and height 0.82 cm.",
    options: ["3.92 cm³", "2.13 cm³", "1.97 cm³", "1.62 cm³"],
    answer: "1.62 cm³",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The locus of a point equidistant from the intersection of lines 3x - 7y + 7 = 0 and 4x - 6y + 1 = 0 is a",
    options: [
      "line parallel to 7x + 13y + 8 = 0",
      "circle",
      "semicircle",
      "bisector of the line 7x + 13y + 8 = 0",
    ],
    answer: "circle",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The gradient of the straight line joining the points P(5, -7) and Q(-2, -3) is",
    options: ["12", "25", "-47", "-23"],
    answer: "-23",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The distance between the point (4, 3) and the intersection of y = 2x + 4 and y = 7 - x is",
    options: ["√13", "3√2", "√26", "10√5"],
    answer: "3√2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the equation of the line through the points (-2, 1) and (-1/2, 4)",
    options: ["y = 2x - 3", "y = 2x + 5", "y = 3x - 2", "y = 2x + 1"],
    answer: "y = 2x + 5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A man stands on a tree 150 cm high and sees a boat at an angle of depression of 74°. Find the distance of the boat from the base of the tree.",
    options: ["52 cm", "43 cm", "40 cm", "15 cm"],
    answer: "43 cm",
  },
  {
    question: "If y = x² - 1/x, find dy/dx",
    options: ["2x - 1/x²", "2x + x²", "2x - x²", "2x + 1/x²"],
    answer: "2x + 1/x²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The mean of seven numbers is 96. If an eighth number is added, the mean becomes 112. Find the eighth number.",
    options: ["126", "180", "216", "224"],
    answer: "224",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the median of 2, 3, 7, 3, 4, 5, 8, 9, 9, 4, 5, 3, 4, 2, 4, and 5",
    options: ["9", "8", "7", "4"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the range of 4, 9, 6, 3, 2, 8, 10 and 11",
    options: ["11", "9", "8", "4"],
    answer: "9",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the standard deviation of 2, 3, 8, 10 and 12",
    options: ["3.9", "4.9", "5.9", "6.9"],
    answer: "3.9",
  },
  {
    question: "Evaluate C(n+1, n-2) if n = 15",
    options: ["3630", "3360", "1120", "560"],
    answer: "560",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In how many ways can the letters of the word TOTALITY be arranged?",
    options: ["6720", "6270", "6207", "6027"],
    answer: "6720",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The probability that a student passes a physics test is 2/3. If he takes three physics tests, what is the probability that he passes two of the tests?",
    options: ["4/9", "6/9", "4/27", "2/27"],
    answer: "4/9",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The probabilities that a man and his wife live for 80 years are 2/3 and 3/5 respectively. Find the probability that at least one of them will live up to 80 years.",
    options: ["2/15", "3/15", "7/15", "13/15"],
    answer: "13/15",
  },
  {
    question: "Convert 2710 to another number in base three",
    options: ["11003", "10003", "10013", "10103"],
    answer: "10003",
  },
  {
    question:
      "3 girls share a number of apples in the ratio 5:3:2. If the highest share is 40 apples, find the smallest share",
    options: ["16", "38", "36", "24"],
    answer: "16",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Calculate the time taken for ₦3000 to earn ₦600 if invested at 8% simple interest",
    options: ["3 years", "1 year", "2 years", "8 years"],
    answer: "2 years",
  },
  {
    question: "If log10 4 = 0.6021, evaluate log10",
    options: ["1.8063", "0.2007", "0.3011", "0.9021"],
    answer: "0.6021",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If P = {x : x is odd, -1 < x ≤ 20} and Q = {y : y , -2 < y ≤ 25}, find P ∩ Q",
    options: [
      "{3, 5, 7, 11, 13, 17, 19}",
      "{2, 3, 5, 7, 11, 13, 17, 19}",
      "{3, 5, 7, 11, 17, 19}",
      "{3, 5, 11, 13, 17, 19}",
    ],
    answer: "{3, 5, 7, 11, 17, 19}",
  },
  {
    question: "If x - 4 is a factor of x² - x - k, then k is",
    options: ["20", "2", "4", "12"],
    answer: "12",
  },
  {
    question: "The remainder when 6p³ - p² - 47p + 30 is divided by p - 3 is",
    options: ["63", "18", "21", "42"],
    answer: "42",
  },
  {
    question:
      "P varies jointly as m and u, and varies inversely as q. Given that p = 4, m = 3, u = 2, and q = 1, find the value of p when m = 6, u = 4, and q = 8/5",
    options: ["10", "288/5", "128/5", "15"],
    answer: "10",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If r varies inversely as the square root of s and t, how does s vary with r and t?",
    options: [
      "s varies directly as r² and t²",
      "s varies directly as r and t",
      "s varies inversely as r and t²",
      "s varies inversely as r² and t",
    ],
    answer: "s varies inversely as r² and t",
  },
  {
    question: "Evaluate 3(x + 2) > 6(x + 3)",
    options: ["x < -4", "x > 4", "x < 4", "x > -4"],
    answer: "x < -4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the sum of the first two terms of a G.P. is 3, and the sum of the second and the third terms is -6, find the sum of the first term and the common ratio",
    options: ["-5", "5", "-2", "-3"],
    answer: "-5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If a binary operation * is defined by x * y = x + 2y, find 2 * (3 * 4)",
    options: ["14", "26", "24", "16"],
    answer: "24",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the angles of a quadrilateral are (3y+10)°, (2y+30)°, (y+20)°, and 4y°, find the value of y",
    options: ["66°", "12°", "30°", "42°"],
    answer: "12°",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A square tile has a side of 30 cm. How many of these tiles will cover a rectangular floor of length 7.2 m and width 4.2 m?",
    options: ["720", "336", "420", "576"],
    answer: "336",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the length of a chord which subtends an angle of 90° at the center of a circle whose radius is 8 cm",
    options: ["8√3 cm", "4 cm", "8 cm", "8√2 cm"],
    answer: "8√2 cm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A chord of a circle subtends an angle of 120° at the center of a circle with a diameter of 4√3 cm. Calculate the area of the major sector",
    options: ["32π cm²", "4π cm²", "8π cm²", "16π cm²"],
    answer: "16π cm²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The locus of the points which is equidistant from the line PQ forms a",
    options: [
      "perpendicular line to PQ",
      "circle centered at P",
      "circle centered at Q",
      "pair of parallel lines to PQ",
    ],
    answer: "pair of parallel lines to PQ",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the midpoint of the line PQ is (2,3) and point P is (-2,1), find the coordinates of point Q",
    options: ["(8, 6)", "(5, 6)", "(0, 4)", "(6, 5)"],
    answer: "(6, 5)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the equation of the perpendicular bisector of the line joining P (2, 3) and Q (-5, 1)",
    options: [
      "8 + 14 + 13 = 0",
      "8 - 14 + 13 = 0",
      "8 - 14 - 13 = 0",
      "8 + 14 - 13 = 0",
    ],
    answer: "8 - 14 - 13 = 0",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In triangle PQR, if q= 8 cm, r=6 cm, and cos P = √92, find the value of P",
    options: ["√108 cm", "√9 cm", "√92 cm", "10 cm"],
    answer: "√92 cm",
  },
  {
    question: "If tan θ = 3/4, find the value of sin + cos",
    options: ["1 1/3", "1 2/3", "1 3/5", "1 2/5"],
    answer: "1 2/5",
  },
  {
    question: "If y = (2x + 2)³, find dy/dx",
    options: ["3(2 + 2)", "6(2 + 2)²", "3(2 + 2)²", "6(2x + 2)"],
    answer: "6(2x + 2)",
  },
  {
    question: "If y = x sin x, find dy/dx",
    options: [
      "cos x + x sin x",
      "sin x + x cos x",
      "sin x - cos x",
      "cos x - x sin x",
    ],
    answer: "sin x + x cos x",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The radius of a circle is increasing at the rate of 0.02 cm/s. Find the rate at which the area is increasing when the radius of the circle is 7 cm",
    options: ["0.35 cm²/s", "0.88 cm²/s", "0.75 cm²/s", "0.55 cm²/s"],
    answer: "0.88 cm²/s",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the mean of t + 2, 2t - 4, 3t + 2, and 2t",
    options: ["2t + 1", "t", "t + 1", "2t"],
    answer: "2t",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The mean of seven numbers is 10. If six of the numbers are 2, 4, 8, 14, 16, and 18, find the mode",
    options: ["14", "2", "6", "8"],
    answer: "8",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the variance of a set of numbers is 5, 6, 4, 7, and the mean is 5, find the standard deviation",
    options: ["3", "√2", "√3", "2"],
    answer: "2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In how many ways can 3 seats be occupied if 5 people are willing to sit?",
    options: ["5", "120", "60", "20"],
    answer: "60",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the value of 110111₂ + 10100₂",
    options: ["10011111₂", "11010111₂", "100101₂", "10011112"],
    answer: "10011111₂",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A woman bought a grinder for ₦60,000. She sold it at a loss of 15%. How much did she sell it?",
    options: ["₦50,000", "₦53,000", "₦52,000", "₦51,000"],
    answer: "₦51,000",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A man donates 10% of his monthly net earnings to his church. If it amounts to ₦4,500, what is his net monthly income?",
    options: ["₦62,500", "₦40,500", "₦45,000", "₦52,500"],
    answer: "₦45,000",
  },
  {
    question: "If log 7.5 = 0.8751, evaluate 2 log 75 + log 750.",
    options: ["66.253", "6.6252", "6.6253", "66.252"],
    answer: "6.6253",
  },
  {
    question: "Evaluate log₂ 8 + log₂ 16 - log₂ 4",
    options: ["6", "3", "4", "5"],
    answer: "5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If P = {1,2,3,4,5} and P ∪ Q = {1,2,3,4,5,6,7}, list the elements in Q",
    options: ["{5, 7}", "{6}", "{7}", "{6, 7}"],
    answer: "{6, 7}",
  },
  {
    question: "Factorize 2y² - 15xy + 18x²",
    options: [
      "(3y + 2x) (y - 6x)",
      "(2y - 3x) (y + 6x)",
      "(2y - 3x) (y -6x)",
      "(2y + 3x) (y - 6x)",
    ],
    answer: "(2y - 3x) (y -6x)",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the value of k if y -1 is a factor of y³ + 4y² + ky - 6",
    options: ["0", "-6", "-14", "1"],
    answer: "-6",
  },
  {
    question: "y varies directly as w². When y = 8, w = 2. Find y when w = 3",
    options: ["6", "18", "12", "9"],
    answer: "18",
  },
  {
    question:
      "P varies directly as Q and inversely as R. When Q = 36 and R = 16, P = 27. Find the relation between P, Q, and R.",
    options: ["P = 12/QR", "P = Q/12R", "P = 12Q/R", "P = 12QR"],
    answer: "P = 12Q/R",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The 4th term of an A.P. is 13 while the 10th term is 31. Find the 24th term.",
    options: ["69", "89", "75", "73"],
    answer: "73",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the common ratio of the G.P. (√10 + √5)(√10 + 2√5) + ⋯?",
    options: ["5", "√2", "√5", "3"],
    answer: "√5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A binary operation * is defined by x * y = xy. If x * 2 = 12 - x, find the possible values of x",
    options: ["-2", "12", "10", "-1"],
    answer: "-2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How many sides has a regular polygon whose interior angle is 135⁰ each?",
    options: ["8", "12", "10", "9"],
    answer: "8",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the angle of a sector of a circle with radius 10.5 cm is 120°, find the perimeter of the sector.",
    options: ["2.5m", "8.0m", "7.5m", "5.0m"],
    answer: "7.5m",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A cylindrical tank has a capacity of 6160m³. What is the depth of the tank if the radius of its base is 28cm?",
    options: ["8.0m", "7.5m", "5.0m", "2.5m"],
    answer: "8.0m",
  },
  {
    question: "The locus of a dog tethered to a pole with a rope of 4m is a",
    options: [
      "semi-circle with radius 4m",
      "circle with diameter 4m",
      "circle with radius 4m",
      "semi-circle with diameter 4m",
    ],
    answer: "circle with radius 4m",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the mid-point of S(-5, 4) and T(-3, -2)",
    options: ["4, -1", "-4, 2", "4, -2", "-4, 1"],
    answer: "-4, 1",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The gradient of a line joining (x,4) and (1,2) is  . Find the value of x",
    options: ["-5", "5", "3", "-3"],
    answer: "5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the equation of the straight line through (-2, 3) and perpendicular to 4x + 3y - 5 = 0",
    options: [
      "5x - 2y - 11 = 0",
      "3x - 4y + 18 = 0",
      "3x + 2y - 18 = 0",
      "4x + 5y + 3 = 0",
    ],
    answer: "3x - 4y + 18 = 0",
  },
  {
    question: "If y = 4x³ - 2x² + x, find dy/dx",
    options: ["12x² - 4x + 1", "8x² - 2x + 1", "8x² - 4x + 1", "12x² - 2x + 1"],
    answer: "12x² - 4x + 1",
  },
  {
    question: "If y = cos 3x, find dy/dx",
    options: ["-3sin 3x", "sin 3x", "-sin 3x", "3sin 3x"],
    answer: "-3sin 3x",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the minimum value of y = x² - 2x - 3",
    options: ["-4", "4", "1", "-1"],
    answer: "1",
  },
  {
    question: "Evaluate ∫ sin 2x dx",
    options: ["-cos 2x + k", "cos 2x + k", "1/2 cos 2x + k", "-1/2 cos 2x + k"],
    answer: "-1/2 cos 2x + k",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the median of 5, 9, 1, 10, 3, 8, 9, 2, 4, 5, 5, 5, 7, 3, and 6",
    options: ["3", "6", "5", "4"],
    answer: "5",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the standard deviation of 5, 4, 3, 2, 1",
    options: ["√10", "√2", "√3", "√6"],
    answer: "√2",
  },
  {
    question: "Find a square root of 170 - 20√30",
    options: ["2√10 -5", "3√5 -8√6", "2√5 -5√6", "5√5 -2√6"],
    answer: "2√5 -5√6",
  },
  {
    question: "Multiply (x + 3y + 5) by (2x² + 5y + 2)",
    options: [
      "2x³ + 3yx² + 10xy + 15y² + 13y + 10x² + 2x + 10",
      "2x³ + 6yx² + 5xy + 15y² + 31y + 10x² + 2x + 10",
      "2x³ + 3yx² + 5xy + 10y² + 13y + 5x² + 2x + 10",
      "2x³ + 6yx² + 5xy + 15y² + 13y + 10x² + 2x + 10",
    ],
    answer: "2x³ + 6yx² + 5xy + 15y² + 31y + 10x² + 2x + 10",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A force of 5 units acts on a particle in the direction to the east and another force of 4 units acts on the particle in the direction north-east. The resultant of the two forces is",
    options: ["√3 units", "3√ units", "√41 + 20√2 units", "√41 + 202 units"],
    answer: "√41 + 20√2 units",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A ladder resting on a vertical wall makes an angle whose tangent is 2.4 with the ground. If the distance between the foot of the ladder and the wall is 50cm, what is the length of the ladder?",
    options: ["1.3m", "1.1m", "1.2m", "1.8m"],
    answer: "1.3m",
  },
  {
    question:
      "After getting a rise of 15%, a man's new monthly salary is ₦345. How much per month did he earn before the increase?",
    options: ["₦350", "₦396.75", "₦300", "₦293.25"],
    answer: "₦300",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The mean of the numbers 1.2, 1.0, 0.4, 1.4, 0.8, 0.8, 1.2 and 1.1 is",
    options: ["1.5", "0.8", "1.0", "1.05"],
    answer: "1.0",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A solid cylinder of radius 3cm has a total surface area of 36cm². Find its height",
    options: ["2cm", "3cm", "4cm", "5cm"],
    answer: "4cm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When a dealer sells a bicycle for ₦81, he makes a profit of 8%. What did he pay for the bicycle?",
    options: ["₦75", "₦74.52", "₦75", "₦75.52"],
    answer: "₦74.52",
  },
  {
    question: "Write the decimal number 39 to base 2",
    options: ["100111", "110111", "111001", "100101"],
    answer: "100111",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A pentagon has four equal angles. If the size of the fifth angle is 60°, find the size of each of the four equal angles",
    options: ["60°", "108°", "120°", "150°"],
    answer: "120°",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find a two-digit number such that three times the tens digit is 2 less than twice the units digit and twice the number is 20 greater than the number obtained by reversing the digits.",
    options: ["24", "42", "74", "47"],
    answer: "47",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In ΔXYZ, XY = 3 cm, XZ = 5 cm, and YZ = 7 cm. If the bisector of ∠XYZ meets XZ at W, what is the length of XW?",
    options: ["1.5 cm", "2.5 cm", "3 cm", "4 cm"],
    answer: "1.5 cm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Marks scored by some children in an arithmetic test are 5, 3, 6, 9, 4, 7, 8, 6, 2, 7, 8, 4, 5, 2, 1, 0, 6, 9, 0, 8. The arithmetic mean of the marks is",
    options: ["6", "5", "7", "4"],
    answer: "5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The graphical method of solving the equation x³ + 3x² + 4x -28 = 0 is by drawing the graphs of the curves",
    options: [
      "y = x³ and y = 3x² + 4x -48",
      "y = x³ + 3x² + 4x -28 and the line y = 1",
      "y = x³ + 3x² + 4x and y = 28/x",
      "y = x² + 3x + 4 and y = 28/x",
    ],
    answer: "y = x² + 3x + 4 and y = 28/x",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A sector of a circle is bounded by two radii 7 cm long and an arc of length 6 cm. Find the area of the sector",
    options: ["42 cm²", "3 cm²", "21 cm²", "24 cm²"],
    answer: "21 cm²",
  },
  {
    question: "Express 150 kilometers per second in meters per hour",
    options: ["7.8 x 10⁵", "4.5 x 10⁶", "7,800,000", "4.68 x 10⁶"],
    answer: "7,800,000",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The arithmetic mean of the ages of 30 pupils in a class is 15.3 years. One boy leaves the class and one girl is enrolled, and the new average age of the 30 pupils in the class becomes 15.2 years. How much older is the boy than the girl?",
    options: ["30 years", "6 years", "9 years", "3 years"],
    answer: "3 years",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A world congress of mathematicians was held in Nice in 1970 with 800 people participating. There were 300 from Europe, 200 from America, 150 from Asia, 45 from Africa, and 105 from Australia. Representing the above on a Pie Chart, the angle of the sector representing the participants from Asia is",
    options: ["150°", "67.5°", "67°", "135°"],
    answer: "67.5°",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the sum to infinity of the following sequence: 1, 9/10, 9/10², 9/10³",
    options: ["1/10", "9/10", "10/9", "10"],
    answer: "10",
  },
  {
    question: "Given that log 2 = 0.693 and log 3 = 1.097, find log 13.5",
    options: ["1.404", "1.790", "2.598", "2.790"],
    answer: "2.598",
  },
  {
    question: "Without using tables, evaluate log2 4 + log4 2 - log25 5",
    options: ["1/2", "1/5", "0", "2"],
    answer: "1/2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the values of p for which the equation x² - (p-2)x + 2p + 1 = 0 has equal roots.",
    options: ["(0, 12)", "(1, 2)", "(21, 0)", "(4, 5)"],
    answer: "(0, 12)",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve the simultaneous equation 2x - 3y = 10z, 10x - 6y = 5",
    options: [
      "x = 2 1/2, y = 3 1/3",
      "x = 3 1/2, y = 2 1/2",
      "x = 2 1/4, y = 3",
      "x = 3 1/2, y = 2 1/5",
    ],
    answer: "x = 2 1/2, y = 3 1/3",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In ΔXYZ, X⏞KZ = 90°, XK = 15cm, XZ = 25cm, and YK = 8cm. Find the area of ΔXYZ.",
    options: ["180 sq.cm", "20 sq.cm", "160 sq.cm", "320 sq.cm"],
    answer: "160 sq.cm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A crate of soft drinks contains 10 bottles of Coca-Cola, 8 of Fanta, and 6 of Sprite. If one bottle is selected at random, what is the probability that it is NOT a Coca-Cola bottle?",
    options: ["5/12", "1/3", "3/4", "7/12"],
    answer: "7/12",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The gradient of the curve is 2x + 1 and the curve passes through point (2, 0). Find the equation of the curve.",
    options: [
      "y = x² + 7x + 9",
      "y = x² + 7x - 18",
      "y = x² + 10x + 9",
      "y = x² + 14x + 11",
    ],
    answer: "y = x² + 7x - 18",
  },
  {
    question: "Differentiate (cos q - sin q)² with respect to q.",
    options: ["-2 cos 2q", "-2 sin 2q", "1 - 2 cos 2q", "1 - 2 sin 2q"],
    answer: "-2 cos 2q",
  },
  {
    question: "If tan θ = 5/4, find sin²θ - cos²θ.",
    options: ["5/4", "41/9", "9/41", "1"],
    answer: "9/41",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the value of x if the expression kx² + x - 5x - 2 leaves a remainder 2 when it is divided by 2x + 1.",
    options: ["10", "8", "-10", "-8"],
    answer: "-10",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If y = x² - x - 12, find the range of values of x for which y ≥ 0.",
    options: ["x ≤ -3, x ≥ 4", "x < -2, x > 4", "x = 0, x = 2", "x ≥ 3, x ≤ 4"],
    answer: "x ≤ -3, x ≥ 4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A man bought a second-hand photocopying machine for ₦34,000. He served it at a cost of ₦2,000 and then sold it at a profit of 15%. What was the selling price?",
    options: ["₦37,550", "₦40,400", "₦41,400", "₦42,400"],
    answer: "₦41,400",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the radius of a sphere whose surface area is 154 cm².",
    options: ["7.00 cm", "3.50 cm", "3.00 cm", "1.75 cm"],
    answer: "3.50 cm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The sum of the first n terms of the arithmetic progression 5, 11, 17, 23, 29, 35,… is",
    options: ["(3 - 0)", "(3 + 2)", "(3 + 2.5)", "(3 + 5)"],
    answer: "(3 + 2)",
  },
  {
    question: "What value of x will make the function x(4 - x) a maximum?",
    options: ["4", "3", "2", "1"],
    answer: "2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In how many ways can a delegation of 3 be chosen from 5 men and 3 women, if at least 1 man and 1 woman must be included?",
    options: ["15", "28", "30", "45"],
    answer: "30",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A student measures a piece of rope and found that it was 1.26m long. If the actual length of the rope was 1.24m, what was the percentage error in the measurement?",
    options: ["0.40%", "0.01%", "0.25%", "0.80%"],
    answer: "0.80%",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve the inequalities -6 ≤ 4 - 2x < 5 - x.",
    options: ["-1 ≤ x < 6", "-1 < x ≤ 5", "-1 < x < 5", "-1 ≤ x ≤ 6"],
    answer: "-1 < x ≤ 5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A cylindrical pipe 5cm long with radius 7m has one end open. What is the total surface area of the pipe?",
    options: ["100 cm²", "98 cm²", "350 cm²", "749 cm²"],
    answer: "749 cm²",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the standard deviation of 2, 3, 5, and 6.",
    options: ["√5/2", "√10", "√6", "√2/5"],
    answer: "√5/2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Without using tables, evaluate (343)-1/3 × (0.14) - 1 × (25)-1/2.",
    options: ["10", "12", "8", "7"],
    answer: "10",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When the expression pm² + qm + 1 is divided by (m-1), it has a remainder of 2, and when divided by (m+1), the remainder is 4. Find p and q respectively.",
    options: ["2, -1", "-1, 2", "3, -2", "-2, 3"],
    answer: "2, -1",
  },
  {
    question: "Divide 2x³ + 11x² + 17x + 6 by 2x + 1.",
    options: ["x² + 5x + 6", "2x² + 5x + 6", "2x² - 5x + 6", "x² - 5x + 6"],
    answer: "x² + 5x + 6",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the equation of the curve which passes through the point (2, 5) and whose gradient at any point is given by 6x - 5.",
    options: ["6x² - 5x", "6x² + 5x + 5", "3x² - 5x - 5", "3x² - 5x + 3"],
    answer: "3x² - 5x + 3",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Thirty boys and x girls sat for a test. The mean of the boys’ scores and that of the girls were respectively 6 and 8. Find x if the total score was 468.",
    options: ["38", "24", "36", "22"],
    answer: "36",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A car dealer bought a second-hand car for ₦250,000.00 and spent ₦70,000.00 refurbishing it. He then sold the car for ₦400,000.00. What is the percentage gain?",
    options: ["15%", "30%", "40%", "50%"],
    answer: "30%",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Find the value of p if the line joining (p, 4) and (6, -2) is perpendicular to the line joining (2, p) and (-1, 3).",
    options: ["0", "3", "4", "6"],
    answer: "6",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the standard deviation of the numbers 1, 2, 3, 4?",
    options: ["1.118", "0.125", "2.125", "1.031"],
    answer: "1.118",
  },
  {
    question:
      "On a pie chart, there are four scores of which three angles are 45°, 90° and 35°. If the smallest sector represents ₦28.00, how much is the largest sector?",
    options: ["₦96.00", "₦84.00", "₦48.00", "₦42.00"],
    answer: "₦84.00",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The result of missing a fair dice 120 times is summarized above; find the value of x.",
    options: ["19", "20", "21", "22"],
    answer: "20",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Given μ = {even numbers between 0 and 30}, P={Multiple of 6 between 0 and 30}, Q={Multiple of 4 between 0 and 30}, find (P∪Q).",
    options: [
      "{2, 10, 14, 22, 26}",
      "{2, 10, 14, 22, 26}",
      "{2, 4, 14, 18, 26}",
      "{0, 2, 6, 22, 26}",
    ],
    answer: "{2, 10, 14, 22, 26}",
  },
  {
    question: "Factorise completely x-2(x - a² + 4b²).",
    options: [
      "(a - 2b)(c + a - 2b)",
      "(a - 2b)(-a - 2b)",
      "(a - 2b)(c + a - 2b)",
      "(a - 2b)(a + 2b)",
    ],
    answer: "(a - 2b)(c + a - 2b)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "PQRSTN is a regular polygon of side 7cm inscribed in a circle. Find the circumference of the circle PQRSTV.",
    options: ["12cm", "42cm", "44cm", "56cm"],
    answer: "42cm",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The shadow of a pole 5√3 high is 5.5cm. Find the angle of elevation of the sun.",
    options: ["50", "45", "60", "75"],
    answer: "60",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A container has 30 gold medals, 22 silver medals, and 18 bronze medals. If one medal is selected at random from the container, what is the probability that it is not a gold medal?",
    options: ["4/7", "3/7", "11/35", "9/35"],
    answer: "4/7",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The mean height and range of heights 1.35, 1.25, 1.35, 1.40, 1.35, 1.45, 1.50, 1.35, 1.50, and 1.20 are m and r respectively. Find m + r.",
    options: ["1.35", "1.65", "1.95", "3.00"],
    answer: "1.95",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the probability that an integer x, {1 ≤ x ≤ 20} chosen at random is divisible by both 2 and 3?",
    options: ["1/20", "1/3", "3/20", "7/20"],
    answer: "3/20",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A trader bought goats for ₦4000 each. He sold them for ₦180,000 at a loss of 25%. How many goats did he buy?",
    options: ["60", "50", "45", "36"],
    answer: "60",
  },
  {
    question: "If tan θ = 4/3, calculate sin²θ - cos²θ.",
    options: ["16/25", "24/25", "7/25", "9/25"],
    answer: "7/25",
  },
  {
    question: "Factorize completely 9y² - 16x².",
    options: [
      "(3y - 2x)(3y + 4x)",
      "(3y + 4x)(3y + 4x)",
      "(3y + 2x)(3y - 4x)",
      "(3y + 4x)(3y - 4x)",
    ],
    answer: "(3y + 4x)(3y - 4x)",
  },
  {
    question: "Solve the inequalities x² + 2x > 15.",
    options: [
      "x < -3 or x > 5",
      "-5 < x < 3",
      "x < 3 or x > 5",
      "x > 3 or x < -5",
    ],
    answer: "x < -3 or x > 5",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A circle of perimeter 28cm is opened to form a square. What is the maximum possible area of the square?",
    options: ["56 cm²", "49 cm²", "98 cm²", "28 cm²"],
    answer: "49 cm²",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Teams P and Q are involved in a game of football. What is the probability that the game ends in a draw?",
    options: ["1/4", "1/3", "1/2", "2/3"],
    answer: "1/3",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the remainder when x³ - 2x² + 3x - 3 is divided by x² + 1.",
    options: ["2x - 1", "x + 3", "2x + 1", "x - 3"],
    answer: "2x - 1",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a class of 60 students, 30 offer physics and 40 offer chemistry. If a student is picked at random from the class, what is the probability that the student offers both physics and chemistry?",
    options: ["1/3", "1/4", "1/2", "1/6"],
    answer: "1/4",
  },
  {
    question: "Express the product of 0.00043 in Standard form.",
    options: ["8.6 × 10", "8.6 × 10-3", "8.6 × 10-2", "8.6 × 10-1"],
    answer: "8.6 × 10-3",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the value of u if y - 1 is a factor of y² + 4y² + 4y - 6.",
    options: ["0", "-6", "-4", "1"],
    answer: "-6",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the angle of a sector of a circle with radius of 10.5cm is 100°. Find the perimeter of the sector.",
    options: ["2.5 m", "3.0 m", "7.5 m", "5.0 m"],
    answer: "3.0 m",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A construction company is owned by two partners and it is agreed that their profit will be divided in the ratio 4:5 at the end of the year. If one partner received ₦5,000 more than the other, what is the total profit of the company per year?",
    options: ["₦20,000", "₦25,000", "₦50,000", "₦45,000"],
    answer: "₦45,000",
  },
  {
    question: "If y = 1 / (3 - 2y² - 5y + 6). Find the other roots.",
    options: ["-3 and 2", "-2 and 2", "3 and -2", "1 and 3"],
    answer: "-2 and 2",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If x + 2 and x - 1 are factors of the expression x³ + 2x² + l x + k, find the value of l and k.",
    options: [
      "L = -6, k = -2",
      "L = -2, k = 1",
      "L = -2, k = -1",
      "L = 0, k = -1",
    ],
    answer: "L = -2, k = 1",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Correct each of the following 59.81798 and 0.0746829 to three significant figures and multiply them giving your answer to three significant figures.",
    options: ["4.46", "4.48", "4.47", "4.49"],
    answer: "4.47",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One interior angle of a convex hexagon is 170° and each of the remaining angles is equal to x°. Find x.",
    options: ["120°", "110°", "105°", "102°"],
    answer: "110°",
  },
  {
    question: "Convert 2415 to base 8.",
    options: ["718", "1078", "1768", "2418"],
    answer: "1078",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A train moves from P to Q at an average speed of 40km/hr and immediately returns from Q to P at 45km/hr. Find the average speed for the entire journey.",
    options: ["55 km/hr", "50 km/hr", "67.50 km/hr", "75 km/hr"],
    answer: "50 km/hr",
  },
  {
    question:
      "By selling 20 oranges for ₦1.35, a trader makes a profit of ₦82. What is his percentage gain or loss if he sells the same 20 oranges for ₦1.10?",
    options: ["8%", "10%", "12%", "15%"],
    answer: "10%",
  },
  {
    question: "Find the eleventh term of the progression 4, 8, 16, ...",
    options: ["213", "212", "211", "216"],
    answer: "212",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In how many ways can 6 subjects be selected from 10 subjects for an examination?",
    options: ["218", "216", "215", "210"],
    answer: "210",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Calculate the simple interest on ₦1,500 for 8 years at 5% per annum.",
    options: ["₦5,000", "₦600", "₦500", "₦150"],
    answer: "₦600",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Two cars x and y start at the same point and travel towards a point P which is 150km away. If the average speed of y is 60km per hour and x arrives at P 25 minutes earlier than y, what is the average speed of x?",
    options: ["51 3/9 km/hr", "72 km/hr", "66 km/hr", "37 ½ km/hr"],
    answer: "72 km/hr",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The first term of an Arithmetic Progression is 3 and the fifth term is q. Find the number of terms in the progression if the sum of the terms is 81.",
    options: ["12", "27", "9", "50"],
    answer: "12",
  },
];
